

## **Professional Summary**

Creative and proactive Frontend Engineer with more than 3.5+ years of experience in building stable and responsive websites, collaborative environments. Highly skilled in HTML, CSS and JavaScript frameworks. Team player able to work in a multidisciplinary and multicultural environment with a passion for usability and responsive design.

## Soft Skills

- Teamwork
- Time management
- Problem solving
- Adaptable
- Creative
- Self-management
- Lateral thinking
- Divergent thinking
- Self-Motivated
- Active listening

## **Programming Skills**

- HTML5
- CSS3 SaSS
- JavaScript
- Vue Js
- React Js
- React Native
- Bootstrap
- GitLab/GitHub
- Redux
- OpenTok

- Python
- Node Is
- API REST
- API GraphQL
- Sentry
- mySQL
- Google Cloud
- Jira
- React Native Firebase

## Language

- English
  Level C1 Advanced Fluency
- **Spanish** *Mother Tongue*
- Italian
  Level B1

# Agustina Ruidiaz

#### FRONTEND ENGINEER

## **Contact Details**

Address: Via Degli Studi 65 - Pozzallo (Ragusa), Italy

Mobile: +39 351 8941623

Email: agusnahirruidiaz@gmail.com

**Portfolio:** https://agusruidiazgd.netlify.app/ **GitHub:** <u>https://github.com/agusruidiazgd</u>

LinkedIn: /agusruidiaz

## **Work Experience**

#### LEAD FRONT END DEVELOPER

Medvice - Freelancer May 2022 - Present

- Worked with React JS in order to implement dashboard new designs and features of an Telemedicine App.
- Ongoing maintenance of the Telemedicine App in React
  Native
- Used Storybook and Tailwind for Styles
- CD/CI Tools Heroku (web) and Bitrise (mobile)
- Code revision with Back End team members

# REACT NATIVE DEVELOPER

**UMA Health Feb 2021** - Feb 2022

- Project: App mobile for Telemedicine platform for booking medical consultation appointments, self diagnostic with Al and machine learning.
- Development and distribution of native apps (both for Android and IOS) using React Native (Firebase DB) - in line with ES6 good practices.
- Authentication, Firebase DB, Crashlytics and analytics
- Implementing machine learning with front end development
- Mobile Development with framework React Native (Typescript), including integration with Redux and Firebase.
- Unit testing (Jest for React)
- Worked with Xcode iOS Dev Program to build and conduct A/B testings (TestFlight)
- Use of native tools with Gradle, Android Studio and Google Play Console in order to - create .apk and test them.

# SEMI SENIOR FRONTEND DEVELOPER

Octosoft Professionals Feb 2021 - Current

- Projects: Virtual library application, NFT Gallery Marketplace, Landings.
- Associate partner in the development area for projects with React Js, Gatsby and Meterial UI
- Provided training and guidance to new hires
- Adapted to the client's ongoing changes while providing results on a tight deadline
- Incentivized live work sessions in order to create a unified workplace

# SOFTWARE ENGINEER

BLOCKINAR Nov 2019 - Jan 2021

- Collaborated with product team members to implement new features.
- Used on a daily basis Scrum and Kanban methodology to streamline the workflow.
- Implemented SEO practices with Vue.Js, with in order to reduce churn and create more customer engagement.
- Worked with multiple teams in order to define the MVP and assist with the development.
- AMP implementation
- Used python for integrations with 3rd party API and website rendering

## **Education ADA ITW**

400hs course - Febrary 2020 - October 2020

- HTML5 CSS3 (Sass processor) React Js
- Vanilla JavaScript
- Jest (testing)

#### **UTN (NATIONAL TECHNOLOGICAL UNIVERSITY)**

Bachelor's in Textile Engineering - March 2014 - March 2020

• Textile Engineering Degree (Complete)

# **Courses and Workshops**

- Agile Scrum
  - May 2020 KUBADILI
- Fundaments and UX Methodology

July 2020 - CHISPA LAB

Figma (prototype / layout)